School of Engineering and Applied Science Records, 1884-2017: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 3: Departments and Centers, 1834-2002 August; 36.36 linear feet 35 boxes
  - Subseries 3D: Department of of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, 1834-1970; 22.42 linear feet 18 boxes
    - Bicentennial Conference, 1948; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 17)
    - Bicentennial, 1946; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 18)
    - Boeing Aircraft Company, 1947; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 19)
    - Budget A-140-A-303, 1943-1944; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 20)
    - Budget Material, 1942-1945; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 21)
    - Budget, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 22)
    - Buick Engine, 1943; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 23)
    - Building Correspondence and Memos, 1943-1950; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 24)
    - Building Plans, undated; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 25)
    - Priority Certificate, 1944; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 26)
    - C - General, 1941-1949; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 27)
    - Catalogue Material, 1947; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 28)
    - Cessna, 1946-1950; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 29)
    - Civil Air Regulations, 1948-1950; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 30)
    - Charyk, J. V, 1952; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 31)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1942-1944; 1 folder (Box 145, Folder 32)
    - Condit, Kenneth H, 1942-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Contract Correspondence,1949-1953, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Contract Department, 1946-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Controller, 1943-1947; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Cooper, J. C, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Course Evaluation Sheets, 1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Courses and Grades, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Curtiss-Wright Corporation, 1943-1947; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - D - General, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Dedication Party, 1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Department Curriculum, 1944-1953; 2 folders (Box 146, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Departmental Examinations, 1946-1948; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Departmental Examinations, 1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Department Holidays and Summer Hours, 1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Departmental Lists, 1947-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Departmental Memorandums, 1948-1954; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 17)
    - Departmental Photos, undated; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 18)
    - Department Personnel Lists,1950, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 19)
    - E - General, 1942-1943; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 20)
    - Eastern Aircraft, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 21)
    - Edison Conference, 1952; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 22)
    - Examinations, 1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 23)
    - Exams, 1943; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 24)
    - Executive Committee - Engineering School, 1947-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 25)
    - Extension Course, 1944; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 26)
    - Extension Course Attendance, 1944; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 27)
    - F - General, 1942-1948; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 28)
    - Faculty Meetings - Minutes, 1946-1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 29)
    - Fales, Elisha N, 1942; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 30)
    - Forrestal Campus, 1941-1954; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 31)
    - Funding, 1941-1950; 12 folders
      - 1950 Fund Campaign, 1949-1950, 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 32)
      - Departmental Fund Campaign, 1946; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 33)
      - Research Fund, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 34)
      - Richard L. Perry Memorial Fund, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 35)
      - W. G. Hildebrant Fund, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 36)
      - George H. Hauser Fund, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 37)
      - Third Century Fund, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 38)
      - Fund Campaign, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 39)
      - Watson, Helen Hayes, 1943; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 40)
      - Laurence Rockefeller Fund, 1941-1949; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 41)
      - Brochure Material (Fund Program), 1941-1942; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 42)
      - Fund Possibilities, 1944-1946; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 43)
    - G and A Aircraft Incorporated, 1944; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 44)
    - G - General, 1941-1948; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 45)
    - General Electric Company, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box 146, Folder 46)
    - Goldberg, 1944; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Graduate Council, 1944-1948; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Grounds and Buildings, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Guggenheim Project, 1947-1950; 3 folders (Box 147, Folder 4 to 6)
    - H - General, 1942; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - Helicopter, 1946-1953; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Helicopter Book, 1944-1946; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - Hughes Aircraft Company Wind Tunnel Test, 1949; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - Hughes Fellowship, 1951; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - Institute of Aeronautical Sciences, 1943-1950; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Inventions Submitted to Department, 1950; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - International Civil Aviation Organization, 1950; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - J - General, 1941-1947; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 15)
    - Jeffery Manufacturing Company, 1948; 3 folders (Box 147, Folder 16 to 18)
    - Johnston, S. Paul, 1943-1944; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 19)
    - K - General, 1942-1948; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 20)
    - Kellett Autogiro Corporation, 1942-1948; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 21)
    - L - General, 1942-1949; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 22)
    - Lectures, undated; 2 folders (Box 147, Folder 23 to 24)
    - Library Material, 1946-1949; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 25)
    - Library Projects, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 26)
    - Library Material, 1946-1948; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 27)
    - Library Lunch Room Committee, 1949; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 28)
    - Luscombe Airplane, 1941-1942; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 29)
    - Limitations on World Air Conference, 1948; 1 folder (Box 147, Folder 30)
    - M - General, 1941-1949; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Mc - General, 1941-1948; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - McDonnell Aircraft, 1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Martin, Harold C, 1943-1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Miller, K. Dexter, 1943-1945; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous 1943 Correspondence, 1943-1944, 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Worksheets, 1942; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Murray-Way Corporation, 1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - N - General, 1942-1947; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics Tunnel Program, 1949; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - National Air Council, 1945-1950; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 12)
    - Naval Research Laboratory Report, "A Ballistic Pendulum Air Draft Measurement Technique", undated; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 13)
    - Nikolsky, A. A., "Proposed Flight Stress Analysis Criteria for Rotary Wing Aircraft", 1943; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 14)
    - O - General, 1942-1947; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 15)
    - Orders, Bills, and Invoices, 1943-1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder F .16)
    - Other Laboratories, 1947-1953; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 17)
    - P - General, 1942-1958; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 18)
    - Petty Cash, 1943-1946; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 19)
    - Pratt and Whitney Engine, 1942-1946; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 20)
    - President's Report, undated; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 21)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 22)
    - Princeton Aviation Sub-Committee, 1946; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 23)
    - Princeton Summer Camp, 1942; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 24)
    - Princeton University Press, 1941-1942; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 25)
    - Proposed Research Blanks, undated; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 26)
    - Prospective Employees, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 27)
    - Publications, 1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 28)
    - R - General, 1941-1950; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 29)
    - Raymond Engineering, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 30)
    - Readjustment Bulletin, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 31)
    - Rejected Proposals, 1946; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 32)
    - Requests for Academic Info, 1946; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 33)
    - Requests for Reports, 1949; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 34)
    - Research Corporation, 1945; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 35)
    - Research Possibilities, 1949; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 36)
    - Riparbelli, Carlo, 1948; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 37)
    - Rocket Society Incorporated, American, 1950; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 38)
    - Rotary Wing Course, 1943; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 39)
    - "A Proposed Center at Princeton University for Training and Research in Rotary Wing Aircraft Design", 1943; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 40)
    - Rotary Wing Prospects for Second Course, 1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 41)
    - Rotary Wing, Third Course, 1944; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 42)
    - Rotor Aircraft Guild, 1944-1947; 1 folder (Box 148, Folder 43)
    - S - General, 1945-1953; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Sayre - Personal, 1942-1947; 2 folders (Box 149, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Secrecy Agreement, 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Secrecy and Publication Policy, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Shipping Forms, 1943; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Sikes, Gordon G, 1943-1945; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Sikorsky, 1942-1948; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Smith, D. I., Aerodynamics Lab, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Society of Automotive Engineers, 1945-1946; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Squid Technical Reports Blanks, undated; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Staff Possibilities, 1941-1953; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Students, 1943-1957; 87 folders
      - Departmental Undergraduates, 1947; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 13)
      - Graduate School Applications, 1943-1948; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 14)
      - Graduate School Office Correspondence, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 15)
      - Graduate School Office, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 16)
      - Graduate School Applications, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 17)
      - Graduate School Lists and Grades, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 18)
      - Graduate Students, 1946-1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 19)
      - Navy Graduate Students, 1948-1950; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 20)
      - Departmental Graduates, 1944-1948; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 21)
      - Officer Graduate Students, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 22)
      - Hunter, W, undated; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 23)
      - Guggenheim Fellowships in Jet Propulsion Applicants, 1945-1957; 74 folders
        - Incomplete Applications,1949-1953, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 24)
        - Abrahamsen, Arthur Norman, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 25)
        - Ahrens, Rudolf Martin, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 26)
        - Allen, Thomas Keith, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 27)
        - Barton, Charles K, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 28)
        - Brown, Fielding, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 29)
        - Bunnell, Gilbert Franklin Jr, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 30)
        - Cangelosi, Victor, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 31)
        - Castaldi, Basilio, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 32)
        - Christhilf, Franklin Donald, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 33)
        - Cutchis, Pythagoras, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 34)
        - Dallafior, Ernest P, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 35)
        - Flickinger, Paul J, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 36)
        - Florence, Mitchell, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 37)
        - Foderaro, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 38)
        - Foster, Eugene L, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 39)
        - Gaunt, Stanley, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 40)
        - Gloumakoff, Nicholas A, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 41)
        - Gray, Robin, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 42)
        - Harrelson, McLeod, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 43)
        - Hartnett, James Patrick, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 44)
        - Harwell, Malcolm J, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 45)
        - Hunter W, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 46)
        - Irlandi, Santo Anthony, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 47)
        - Jackson, Alden H, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 48)
        - Johnson, Warne P, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 49)
        - Johnson, Raymond M, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 50)
        - Kershner, Donald Warner, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 51)
        - Kleinman, Harold, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 52)
        - Kistler, Wallace J, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 53)
        - Kuang-Chun, Chau, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 54)
        - Lantz, Edward, 1945; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 55)
        - Lee, Chai-Sung, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 56)
        - Lehrer, Stanley, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 57)
        - Levin, Stuart M, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 58)
        - Liston, Hardy Jr, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 59)
        - Lovett, Daniel Bruce, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 60)
        - Malkiel, Saul, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 61)
        - Marshall, E. V, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 62)
        - McCabe, Warren Lee, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 63)
        - Michael, William H, undated; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 64)
        - Miller, John S, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 65)
        - Moffett, Kenneth D, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 66)
        - Nelson, Russell Charles, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 67)
        - Okada, Koyo, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 68)
        - Orofino, Thomas A, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 69)
        - Overbey, James T, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 70)
        - Patterson, William Roy, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 71)
        - Peterson, Robert E, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 72)
        - Peirce, Thomas Edwin, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 73)
        - Reiter, Sydney Howard, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 74)
        - Rizika, Jack Wilford, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 75)
        - Seckel, Edward, undated; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 76)
        - Schemel, George J, 1957; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 77)
        - Segal, Manase, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 78)
        - Shapiro, Henry Leon, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 79)
        - Shell, Donald Lewis, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 80)
        - Sherman, Arthur, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 81)
        - Shipp, Lawrence Ralph, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 82)
        - Smith, R. D, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 83)
        - Smith, Alan Bowen, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 84)
        - Spicer, Willis J, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 85)
        - Stanski, Walter, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 86)
        - Stein, Ralph R, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 87)
        - Summers, Richard G, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 88)
        - Sung, Tsai-Chen, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 89)
        - Van Builten, Robert, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 90)
        - Vieira, Ernest C, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 91)
        - Wilson, Richard Lee, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 92)
        - Walden, Jack Robert, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 93)
        - White, Douglas F, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 94)
        - Wood, Henry L, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 95)
        - Wood, Robert McLane, 1949; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 96)
        - Hjortsvang, Kenneth W, 1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 97)
      - Grad Students - "Form G", 1950; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 98)
      - Graduate School Admissions Requirements, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 149, Folder 99)
    - Summerfield, Martin, 1949-1952; 3 folders
      - Unpaid Travel Vouchers, 1952; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 1)
      - General, 1949; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 2)
      - Paid Travel Vouchers, 1949-1952; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - T - General, 1943-1953; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Teaching Assignments, 1946-1948; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Technical Reports, 1941; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Telegrams, Long Distance Calls, Etc, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Tests on Industrial Items, 1948; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Theses, Instructions for Preparation of, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Third Ice Contract, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Tifford, Arthur, 1946; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Toledo Scales Company, 1942; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Travel Vouchers, 1946; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Tunnel, Supersonic #1, 1947; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - U - General, 1944-1947; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - United States Surplus Property, 1945; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - V - General, 1942-1948; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Visiting Fellows and Scientists, 1950; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - W - General, 1941-1950; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - Wagner Lecture, 1948; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 20)
    - Warner Aircraft Corp, 1947; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 21)
    - Wilford, E. Burke, 1944; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 22)
    - Wind, Power from the, 1954; 3 folders (Box 150, Folder 23 to 25)
    - Wind Tunnel Equipment, 1951; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - Wind Tunnel Designs, Plan, Etc, 1946-1949; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 27)
    - Wind Tunnel Miscellaneous, 1947-1954; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 28)
    - Woodrow, R. J, undated; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 29)
    - X, Y, Z - General, 1946; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 30)
    - May, Agnes F, 1942 October 2; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 31)
    - Daily Calendar, 1952; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 32)
    - Research Reports, 1952 October 15-1955; 18 folders
      - "Viscous Effects in Supersonic Flow", 1952 October 15-1953 April 15; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 33)
      - "A Study of Shock Wave Turbulent Boundary", 1953 July 22; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 34)
      - "Preliminary Interferometric Evaluations of Shock-Boundary Layer Interaction in the Laminar and Transitional Range", 1953 May 15; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 35)
      - "Viscous Effects in Supersonic Flow", 1953 July 15; 1953 October 15; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 36)
      - "Investigation of Hypersonic Flows", 1953 July 15; 1953 October 15; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 37)
      - "Combustion Instability in Liquid Propellant Rocket Motors", 1953 November 1-1954 January 31; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 38)
      - "Outline of Present and Proposed Activities of the Subsonic Aerodynamics Group", 1954 April; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 39)
      - "Investigation of Hypersonic Flows", 1954 April 15-1954 October 15; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 40)
      - "Combustion Instability in Liquid Propellant Rocket Motors", 1954 May 1-1954 July 1; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 41)
      - "Determination of the Effective Axial Induced Flow Pattern Through a Helicoptor Rotor From Pressure Measurements", 1954; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 42)
      - "Combustion Instability in Liquid Propellant Rocket Motors", 1954 August 1-1954 October 31; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 43)
      - "Sixth Meeting of the AGARD Flight Test Panel", 1954 November 29-1954 December 4; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 44)
      - "Combustion Instability in Liquid Propellant Rocket Motors", 1954 November 1-1955 January 31; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 45)
      - "A Theoretical Analysis of the Lateral Dynamic Stability of Tandem Helicopters", 1955; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 46)
      - "Research on Laminar and Turbulent Boundary Layers and Transition at Supersonic Speeds", 1954 December 31-1955 March 31; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 47)
      - "Analytic Development of the Optimum Flight Path Equations", 1955 March 16; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 48)
      - "Viscous Effects in Supersonic Flow", 1955 March 1; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 49)
      - "Combustion Instability in Liquid Propellant Rocket Motors", 1955 April 1; 1 folder (Box 150, Folder 50)
    - A, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Applicants, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Council, 1948-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Assistantships, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - B, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Baetjer Fund, 1950; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Boundary Layer - Paraplane, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - C, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Chase Aircraft, 1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - Condit, K. H, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - D, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - E, 1951; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - Examinations, 1951-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - F, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 15)
    - G, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 16)
    - H, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 17)
    - I, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 18)
    - Invoices, 1951-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 19)
    - J, undated; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 20)
    - K, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 21)
    - L, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 22)
    - M, undated; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 23)
    - N, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 24)
    - Newmyer and Bress, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 25)
    - Union Trust Company v. Eastern Air Lines, Incorporated Court Documents, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 26)
    - O, 1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 27)
    - P, Q, undated; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 28)
    - Perkins (Consulting), 1949-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 29)
    - Placement Recommendations, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 30)
    - Purchase Order, 1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 31)
    - R (Including Receipts), 1951-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 32)
    - Requests for Reports, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 33)
    - S, 1948-1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 34)
    - T, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 35)
    - U, V, undated; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 36)
    - W, X, Y, Z, undated; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 37)
    - Class and Examination Schedules, 1952-1953; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 38)
    - Forrestal Memorial, 1951-1952; 2 folders
      - Dedication Ceremony - Armed Services Day, 1952; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 39)
      - Publicity, 1951; 1 folder (Box 151, Folder 40)
    - Sayre, Daniel, 1942; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1937-1943; more than 37 folders
      - Aeroplane Spotters, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 2)
      - Aircraft Armament, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 3)
      - Applications of Plastics and Plywood,1941, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 4)
      - Aviation Sketch Books, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 5)
      - Boeing Aircraft, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 6)
      - Bell Aircraft Corporation, 1938; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 7)
      - Bellanca Aircraft Corporation, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 8)
      - Brewster Aeronautical Corporation, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - Consolidated Aircraft Corporation, 1938; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 10)
      - Culver Aircraft Corporation, undated; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 11)
      - Curtiss-Wright Corporation, 1940; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 12)
      - Directory, 1941; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 13)
      - Douglas Aircraft Incorporated, 1939; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 14)
      - Fairchild Aircraft Division, 1937; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 15)
      - Fleetwings Incorporated, 1940; 1 folder (Box 152, Folder 16)